all right
[Music]
vision is not the only sense associated
with physical attractiveness and partner
preference body odor signals a variety
of information not matter such as eating
habits hygiene health and more based on
a survey of hundreds of college students
men rated Visual and smell information
as being equally important for selecting
a lover oh while women considered how
their potential mates smell to be the
single most important variable in other
words women ranked body odor as more
important for attraction than looks
I've talked about the concern around
aluminum containing antiperspirants what
can we do to make ourselves smell better
clinical studies dating back to the
1950s show that chlorophyll can be used
to improve body odors this led to a wave
of commercial chlorophyll deodorant
products but as one chlorophyll
scientist lamented because of the
unfounded fantastic and sometimes
completely idiotic claims made for
chlorophyll by the promotion in
advertising men the buying public as
well as the scientist will remain
skeptical and rightly so
to Be an Effective deodorant chlorophyll
has to be taken internally at doses that
far exceed those found in so-called
deodorizing chewing gums and lozenges
studies showing the elimination of
detectable underarm odors used doses on
the order of a 100 milligrams a day
in other words the amount of chlorophyll
one could get in about a third of a
bunch of raw spinach so before
slathering aluminum onto your skin I
recommend first trying to deodorize From
the Inside Out by eating a big salad
every day which may improve your body
odor two ways hitting the chlorophyll
threshold and improving your health
there is a cent to disease some diseases
result in a characteristic odor
emanating from sick individuals for
example tuberculosis of the throat makes
you smell like stale beer typhoid makes
you smell like baked bread that doesn't
sound so bad though yellow fever makes
you smell like a butcher shop
but it's not just infection I mean
evolutionarily wouldn't it be
advantageous if you could smell the
first signs of inflammation immune
system activation to stay away from
people before they become contagious
what this team of researchers did was
inject people with endotoxin which is a
highly inflammatory component of certain
bacterial cell walls caused a big spike
of internal inflammation and the
question is could you smell it on people
within just a few hours
endotoxin-exposed individuals had a more
aversive body odor relative to when they
were exposed to a placebo
a significantly Less Pleasant body odor
within hours moreover the more inflamed
they got the worse they smelled
providing the first experimental
evidence that we can smell inflammation
on people
and guess where endotoxins are found in
the food supply where bacteria are found
in meat and they're not destroyed by
cooking a whole series of videos about
that we know meat causes inflammation so
does that mean it makes people smelly
you don't know
uh until you put it to the test the
effect of meat consumption on body odor
attractiveness not just body odor but
body odor attractiveness for two weeks
male odor donors were placed on a diet
that included meat or excluded meat a no
meat diet and then during the final 24
hours they had pads taped into their
armpits to collect their body odor then
the researchers just needed some judges
to sniff the pads from each of the men
so fresh odor Samples hot off the pits
less than an hour old were assessed for
their pleasantness attractiveness
masculinity and intensity by 30 women
a month later the study was repeated
with the same guys but now following the
other diet the same poor women were used
as judges the men incidentally were paid
2 000 in Czech currency for their time
and potential inconvenience caused by
the prescribed diet but the women who
had to sniff all those armpit pads the
Raiders were not paid for their
participation though did get a chocolate
bar after the second session
so who had the most Pleasant the most
attractive body odor the results showed
that the odor of donors went on the
non-meat diet was judged as
significantly more attractive more
pleasant and less intense no difference
was noted for masculinity
the researchers conclude that meat may
have a negative impact on perceived body
odor hedonicity in other words those
even more plant-based evidently smell
significantly more pleasurable
oh